# Mélisande Yung

# Marketing manger

3 years at Rakuten , as e-commerce marketing project manager and marketing assistant (fashion and beauty sector). I increased the number of visitors there by 30% and increased the conversion rate from 1.8% to 4.2%. Mastering the media of digital marketing, social networks and content (CMS and Google Analytics), I can allow your online fashion store to explode in number of visitors and buyers.

# **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES**

December 2017 - Now

Rakuten France, Paris

E-commerce marketing project manager (fashion and beauty sector)

- Develop traffic to the Fashion and Beauty online store (+30% traffic).
- Increase conversion rate (+133%) and reduce bounce rate (-85%).
- Supervise the Marketing and User Interface teams to improve the site and the buying process.
- Plan the budget for web marketing strategies and projects.

November 2016 - December 2017

Rakuten France, Paris

digital marketing assistant

- Manage communications between product, IT and content teams.
- Plan and carry out social media marketing campaigns (+200,000 fans on Facebook, engagement rate increased from 1.2% to 2.9%).
- Analyze the customer database to optimize automatic emails.

April 2016 - September 2016

E-co Solutions, Strasbourg

Webmarketing assistant (6 month internship)

- Conduct a study on the satisfaction of Internet users regarding their e-commerce experiences.
- Evaluate the weak points identified for our customers and propose solutions.
- Plan their digital marketing strategies and produce quotes.

# **EDUCATION**

September 2014 – September 2016

MSc Digital Marketing (master)

Skema Business School, Sophia Antipolis

September 2013 - June 2014

License Pro e-commerce and digital marketing

IUT Aix-Marseille, Aix-en-Provence

#### **SKILLS**

- Marketing and e-commerce strategy
- Budget and project planning
- Online store optimization (conversion rate, visits, etc.)
- Team leader qualities
- Communication



# CONTACT

#### **Address**

15, boulevard Amiral Courbet

**Phone** 0485435365

## **Email**

nom@gmail.com

# **LANGUAGES**

French (C2 Level)

English (B2 Level)

### **HOBBIES**

Football

Course

**Automobile Camping**